MIGUELÁNGEL

NIÑO VARGAS

CONTACT INFO

E-mail miguel.n.vargas@hotmail.com

Phone Nr +57 313 327 0741

Address Carrera 36 17-293 Ciudad Verde

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/manv2

ABOUT ME

Mechatronic engineer with experience in handling large data volumes, ETL management, segmentation, transformation, cleaning and analysis of information for the generation of risk models; strong programming foundations in languages such as (Python, SQL, Java, R), advanced management of Python libraries (Pandas, Numpy, Scikit learn), knowledge in MVC architectures and database management, analysis and generation of impact reports using software (Tableau, PowerBI), bases in probability, statistics, calculation, complemented with basic knowledge in architectures in the cloud (AWS, Azure), English level B2, conversational and written.

EXPERIENCE

DATAMINING FRAUD PREVENTION

2022-Actually

Banco Falabella | Bogotá, Colombia

- Track the operation and KPIs to the fraud investigation teams and frontline controls
- Make continuous improvements to the measurements of fraud indicators and bank transaction authorization indicators
- Process automation, information capture and monitoring directly of the operation and management of corporate reports using tools such as: Big Query, Tableau, Python, Javascript, SQL, Google Sheets, HTML

DATA SCIENTIST 2020-2022

MI BANCO COLOMBIA | Santiago, Chile

(Risk Area - Risk Models Department)

- Supervise and monitor the models in production of the bank
- Perform the role of data modeler to meet the goals of the company
- Carry out the performance and creation of KPI's aimed at continuous improvement of the business

EDUCATION

Master in Data Analytic

2022-Actually

University Central | Bogota, Colombia

• Cumulative career average: 4.8

Mechatronics Engineer

2015-2020

Piloto University of Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia

- Cumulative career average: 4.5
- Two times winner of the Mechatronic Semester Award to the best project

SKILLS

● ● Python, SQL, R, Tableau, PowerBI, AWS (Amazon web Services), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Fraud Prevention, DataAnalisis,

● O Jira, App Script, Javascript, HTML, Google Services, Data-Science

● O O LATEX, Pentaho, Agile Methodologies

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (Full professional proficiency B1)

REFERENCES

Capt. Jack Associate Datamining Partner

Sparrow Fraud Risk Division

https://www.linkedin.com/in/natalia-gonzalez-palacios-

031583165

Kathryn Fraud Prevention Manager Janeway Fredy Barco

Fredy Barco Fraud Risk Division

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fredy-barco-204766102